There are many bottlenecks
when trying to make money online,
and one of the
biggest bottlenecks
is between social media
and getting people's contact
information,
because that's really what we want from
social media.
We want nothing else than to get people's
information.
But if we don't get enough engagement,
followers, people watching our stuff, then
when it comes to
that point of actually asking them for
their email address, we're
not going to get it. There
is a four-stage structure
that I believe in very heavily
for content creation.
If you've seen any of my other videos,
you'll know that.
And it goes brand awareness,
create goodwill on social media,
get someone's
email address,
run a really efficient email marketing
campaign, and from that,
people have to read a certain amount of
emails before they go to your landing
page.
And when they go on your landing page,
they're going to feel compelled to want to
buy your product because it's amazing
and it looks great.
But the problem is,
how do we get people's email addresses?
Well,
first principle we need to understand
is something that I call WIIFM.
What's in it for me?
There has to be something in it for me,
or I'm not just going
to give you my email address.
Because the reason email marketing works
so well for
sales is the same reason it's so difficult
to get people's email address in the
first place. This thing right here
is my inbox, and it's a sacred place.
I'm quite happy with idiots on the
internet having a pop at me,
commenting about my
receding hairline,
saying I've got a mid physique.
But what I can't stand is
when an unsolicited email finds its way
into my
inbox.
I'll be petty enough to go back to
that person and abuse their whole system.
Go, "Listen,
not only did you email me without consent,
brother, you did it from
a Gmail. That's pathetic.
Call yourself a business?" Even if you
are a scammer in
India or you're a fully fledged business
in Australia or the UK or USA, the fact
you had the audacity to try
and sell to me from a Gmail.
This is time I could be spent doing much
more productive things because that email
inbox is sacred. So you
are asking to put your information in
someone's sacred space, and for that,
you must give them something.
Let's look at some of the things
that I do not think are working.
Number one, PDFs. Rinsed, washed.
PDFs were great in 2014,
but it's not 2014 anymore.
Also, if you send someone a resource,
there is the blatantly obvious
occurrence that they're not going to
finish that resource.
Because no one in history has read a
13-page PDF
when it got sent through to them.
They scroll through it, they go, "Yeah,
it's
nice." But there's also psychological
trauma to the fact that if they can't even
finish your free flipping asset
that you sent them, how
are they going to finish a
paid program? There
are people in the fitness industry still
trying to use a
calorie calculator. "Hey, guys,
you want to calorie
and calorie calculate and
calculate?" Rinsed, washed.
The one thing that I do like
using at the moment,
but it's soon to be rinsed
and washed because I think it's
only going to last for the next six
months,
is an autoresponder where you set up an
amount of emails
that hit you every single day,
because at least that could be of
value.
But when it comes to these autoresponders,
although I'm guilty of this,
please have some kind of niche in mind,
but not too niche, because 2024
has really shown us the year of
overniching.
There are content creators online
that only work with lesbians
or gay people.
Like that's a good niche.
Like your problems for fat loss, training,
and
progressive overload
are impacted by your sexuality.
They could be,
but I'm yet to see any evidence
that says you should be using a
different rep range because you like to
rug munch.
Is rug munch derogatory to lesbians?
I don't know.
Lesbians don't use YouTube, we're fine.
But let's say you train people's glutes,
or you're someone that
works in carpentry,
or you're a speech coach.
"Over the next 42 days,
I'm going to give you 42 science-based
proven methods to stop you umming, erring,
and saying like when you
speak on podcasts." This sounds amazing.
"Put in your email address.
I'll send you the first lesson right
away." Fantastic.
Every single type of squeeze
that we use to get someone's email address
can be a
campaign.
We don't have to create our identity
around it.
Squeeze pages I've used have been the
calorie calculator, before it was rinsed,
before it was washed.
I once did a non-binary program just for
banter.
And once I actually put out a program for
dudes under six foot.
It was mostly arms. But ultimately,
if you can understand the niche within
your
business and the problems in
which people are facing,
you should create some kind
of asset that they can download
or get in return for their email address.
Just don't make it boring.
If you're someone
that wants people to eat more protein,
that's the biggest problem
that they have within your niche.
"Oh,
I can't get my clients to eat more
protein." We could give them protein
recipes. Is that niche enough?
How about high protein air fryer recipes
that you
should eat for lunch
that will make it easy to hit your protein
goals? Okay, cool.
Now we're talking.
So we want to give something of value to
that person for their
email address.
And you should try different campaigns
and then see which ones work
the best, and then go down with that.
If you've got five different ways of
obtaining someone's email address,
one of them
is going to outperform the others.
Double down on that.
When it comes to the actual methods of
getting it,
we can try putting it into your
story. We can use chatbots.
We can then put it into reels and, "Hey,
DM me the
word protein and I'll send you something."
That's all good and great.
Another thing that I think we need to
really consider is this kind of comeback
in
2024 of written content. So for instance,
you could put out YouTube videos.
You could put your videos onto LinkedIn,
Facebook, Instagram, TikTok, whatever.
Most of these platforms still permit us to
do some form of written content.
So maybe a LinkedIn post.
The YouTube community wall right now is
fire for getting people's email addresses.
For any of you that don't know,
if you scroll through YouTube enough,
you get
videos, videos, videos,
then you get a picture with text.
So rather than trying to get a call to
action in your video, which can be
difficult. For instance,
if I say in this video, "Hey, guys,
in the description,
there's going to be a link for 30 days
and 30 ways that you can get
business advice from me." Actually,
in fact,
if you just want to copy the email
responder that I give to people to get
their email address, you should use
that one
in the description. But ultimately,
if you can use your community wall,
LinkedIn,
stories, and in Facebook,
you can do text-based stuff.
You can take people on a little journey
where maybe at the end you go, "And if you
give me your email address,
I can help you with that." For Instagram,
not quite so
simple.
One thing that's definitely working,
especially I would say in the last
three months, is carousel posts.
Carousel posts on Instagram can now be up
to
20 different pictures and images.
Scrolling through those,
you could take someone on a journey.
Also with carousel posts, the first
and second image are previewed,
so you get two
bites at the carrot.
And then your last carousel post can be
either use the link in
my bio, which I think is dead.
You should have seen
that maybe in yesterday's
video. Or use the chatbot, which again,
I went through that.
But ultimately, if you
are trying to get people to sign up to
your email list and
no one is doing it, it's because there
is not enough value.
There is not something in it for
that person.
And if you can cultivate
and really get them for that WIIFM,
give something that's
something in it for them,
then you'll get it.
Don't give them a free workout because no
one needs a free workout.
Don't enter them into a challenge.
Don't send them a mug.
Try and think of something
that could really revolutionize
and make someone's day
better. The biggest issue really is this.
When you are trying to obtain email
addresses,
you are trying to help yourself.
You are trying to do something that's
going to make your life better.
Because the more email addresses you have,
the more people go to your landing page.
The more people that go to your landing
page, the more people buy.
Instead, try and flip the script on
that and give them something that can make
their life better. And if you do that,
you'll resonate with it.
So I think that you should rip me off
and steal what I use,
and read the 30 ways in 30 days
that I put in the description.
Because the emotional journey you get over
the next 30 days is exactly the kind of
emotional feeling
and impact I want you to have on the
person that you do business
with, whether coach, yoga instructor,
whatever it is.
So check that out in the description.
Or if you're not interested in that,
it could be that you're not getting enough
views on your content. And
if you want to maybe, I don't know,
figure out how to
get 10,000 views in every single video,
you can watch this.
And once you address this,
you can come back to this video
and worry about how to
get people's email addresses.
Thanks for watching.